one really great tool in the grandma3 software is
the new way of making your presets your macros and
lots of other things look just the way you like it
you can do that with a few different tools and in
this video i'll go through some of the different
functionalities you can use to accomplish the look
you're trying to achieve i'm talking
about appearances. Appearances is a cool
and simple way for you to customize the look of
different aspects of your grandma 3 appearance
you can color almost everything to distinguish
one preset from the other or make your store macro
stand out so you don't press it by mistake so
let's get into this GrandMA3 appearance tutorial
the GrandMA3 appearances can be used to change
the look of a preset macro fader and even the led
light on the physical faders on the real GrandMA3 consoles and it's not even limited to that
you can assign your appearances to a lot of
different places in the console and as you
can see i prepared a little show file for us right
here let's first go into this empty area or create
your own area and let's find our appearances it's
right here that's our appearance tab let's just
make this a little bit smaller and let's
start to uh to see what we can do with it
you have all these appearances right here and they
don't really make any sense to begin with but to
see how appearances work let's start over here in
our master cue lists so if we press this one and
we go into the settings right here you have this
appearances tab right here if you click that one
you can select one of the images i just showed you
over and in the appearance tab but if you go down
to new you get this one up here so let's start
with making a color appearance let's just put
it into red for now like this let's just close it
down and as you can see it's red now let's close
this one down everything over here turned red and
as you can see a new appearance turned up here so
you have the appearance pool and in the appearance
pool every time you build a new appearance it it
comes up here and the cool thing about appearances
is you can use them and you can reuse them so if i
go into my store macro right here and say okay
i want my store macro to be red i can simply
say edit go up into the appearance tab here and
now i can select the red appearance we just made
so we click this one down and this one is now red
the cool thing is then you can say okay i want to
change this appearance i want it to be blue and
as you can see it changed here and it changed up
here so this one over here is a reference we can
use it and we can reuse it everywhere we want so
let's just put it back into red like this this is
our first appearance but appearances is a two-part
thing let's just try to build a new one let's say
edit we have the image color or the foreground
and you have the background color so before
we just use the image color let's just try to
use the background color let's put it into blue
and let's turn the alpha channel all the way up
and let's turn the alpha channel all the way
down on the image color and we clear this one
out then we go into our color cue right here we
go into appearances and as you can see down here
this selects a border around the the fader like
this so if we clear this one down it builds a
border around it so basically we can still change
this and say okay this is our background color
i want to edit this and put it into maybe yellow
on our foreground so we turn this one all the
way up and as you can see it has a background
color of blue and a foreground or image color of
yellow so this is going to change our fader
to look like this the background color affects
the physical faders you you've seen the images
of the real GrandMA3 consoles you have like an
led light on the fader and you can
change the color by using the appearances
and you can use the background color like this so
in this case if we had a real GrandMA3 console
our faders led light would now be blue
because we use the background color
what i just showed you is something you
can use in your GrandMA3 programming
but as with everything else you don't have to
use it you can customize your show file just
the way you like it and how much work you want
to put into it is all up to you you could check
out this next video you can see on your screen
right now it'll guide you to another cool part
of the GrandMA3 software and possibly give
you some new insights of the GrandMA3 software
i hope i see you in the next video but until
i see you again happy GrandMA3 programming